<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Sperte</title>
    <description>Hello. Welcome to the weblog of Sean Sperte. This is a collection of notes related to design, technology, and faith.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 11:59:56 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 11:59:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It turns out, hosting a blog on Tumblr doesn’t help motivate more writing or posting. That, plus the fact that I’ve been meaning to learn about new publishing systems, means it’s time to move things back “in-house”. So I’m back to hosting Geek &amp;amp; Mild myself. Well, not &lt;em&gt;myself&lt;/em&gt; technically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this version I’ve chosen to revive a previous design and use &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; – hosted on Github Pages. I lost some Tumblr posts along the way, but I ain’t cryin’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process to port the site wasn’t too bad. I used a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mrwarren&quot;&gt;Brian Warren’s&lt;/a&gt; tips from his &lt;a href=&quot;http://begoodnotbad.com/article/Migrating-from-ExpressionEngine-to-Kirby&quot;&gt;post about porting ExpressionEngine to Kirby&lt;/a&gt;. Converting all my previous blog entries was a bit of a chore, but the hardest part was learning the Jekyll templating language. (I still haven’t really learned it, actually.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like about this setup is it allows me to draft and publish new posts in a familiar way to which I work: write, save, commit (via git). Once I ‘commit’, git and Jekyll (and Github Pages) do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, Geek &amp;amp; Mild is now open source, so if you’re interested in seeing how I’ve got things hooked up you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sperte/sperte.github.io&quot;&gt;peruse the code&lt;/a&gt; – for now a least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/jekyll</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fairweather</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up watching John Elway lead the likes of Bobby Humphrey, Steve Atwater, Karl Mecklenburg, and others to three Super Bowls in the 80’s. They lost all three – devastatingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Denver Broncos were as good as you can get without being the best. So I became conditioned, even at a young age, to cheer for a team – to believe – with thick skin and strong resolve. Whether winning or losing, my team was my team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the Seahawks were always a non-issue. Back then they were in the same division as the Broncos, in the AFC West. But unlike the Raiders or Chargers, I actually liked the team from Seattle. I had family there, and liked the team colors. I also always found myself rooting for the Seahawks whenever there was another divisional game televised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1998, after moving to Seattle, I watched from a distance as Elway – now with Terrell Davis, Rod Smith, Shannon Sharpe, Ed McCaffery, etc. – finally brought the Lombardi Trophy home to Denver. Apparently it took me leaving the state for the Broncos to find their way. If it wasn’t salt in the wound it was fly in the ointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elway went on to retire a year later, after repeating a Championship season with another win in Super Bowl 33. Fly, ointment; normal. Go Broncos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, in 2002, everything changed. The Seahawks switched conferences, and became an NFC team. That was the year I officially became a Seahawks fan. It was an easy fit, to put my learned and practiced win-or-lose support behind the local team. They hadn’t been contenders for years – if ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until the 2005 season when the Hawks made a valiant Super Bowl run that my fandom reached any sort of passionate level. They lost. Of course. And it would be a couple of years until Seattle made any impact beyond early December. But that didn’t matter. I was a die-hard; a fan-no-matter. Content, and even happy, with cheering on a losing team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, slowly, things changed. John Elway returned… Then Pete Carroll was hired… Then Tim Tebow… Then Peyton Manning… Then Russell Wilson… Then this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the season started this year I told my dad that the Seahawks were going to go all the way – that they had something special. We debated whether or not Peyton could lead Denver the whole way, too. “Wouldn’t it be crazy? Could you imagine a Broncos/Seahawks Super Bowl?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been called “conflicted”, “confused”, and “split-brained”. I love two NFL teams. But how is that possible? Don’t you have to choose one or the other? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I just have the capacity to be passionate about more than one. Maybe, like a parent with more than one child, it’s impossible for me to love one more than the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight as I watched the Seahawks trounce the Broncos in Super Bowl 48, I wasn’t choosing to love one team over another. I was watching as a crazed and committed member of the 12th Man, and a dyed-in-the-wool Broncos fan. Don’t ask me to explain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the game, I sent this text to a buddy of mine: “Love my Broncos, but they’re about to run into the Hawks and get it handed to them. Just like preseason”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what happened. I watched the whole game standing up in my living room – mostly alone. I clapped, cheered, jumped, and screamed … By myself. Alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever feeling of loss, disappointment, or frustration I may have had with the Broncos getting their butts kicked was completely overshadowed by the Seahawks finally, and definitively, earning their place in history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So call me confused, or conflicted, or whatever. Just, whatever you do, don’t you dare call me a fair-weather fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a 12. And I’m United in Orange. If I have a problem it’s not that I love two teams, it’s that I have no idea how to be a fan of a winning team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/fairweather</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/fairweather</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>People of the Internet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is awesome. Actually, no. The &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; of the internet are awesome. The reason I know this is because last week I attended two conferences where I got to be with a lot of them. Some I’d just met, but some I’d been following for years – even a decade or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That term: following. I used it a lot over the last six days. “I’ve been following you for a long time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said it to &lt;a href=&quot;http://shauninman.com/&quot;&gt;Shaun Inman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mezzoblue.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Shea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cameronmoll.com/&quot;&gt;Cameron Moll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tincorporated.com/&quot;&gt;Tom Watson&lt;/a&gt; (well, his wife, actually), &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewwarkentin.com/&quot;&gt;Drew Warkentin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.ugmonk.com/&quot;&gt;Jeff Sheldon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brandclay.com/&quot;&gt;Sean Ferrell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://paularmstrong.me/&quot;&gt;Paul Armstrong&lt;/a&gt;, and many others. What I realized is that I’d been “following” these people long before Twitter, so the statement sounded trite and didn’t communicate the level of respect I have them. What I wanted to tell them, actually, was that their work had inspired and mentored me from afar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circles Conference was held in Dallas and organized by &lt;a href=&quot;http://burciaga.co/&quot;&gt;Ismael Burciaga&lt;/a&gt;. Its emphasis was on creativity, design, and art – and, ultimately, the inspiration of all those things. The talks themselves were great, and I enjoyed hearing from every speaker. But I was more inspired by meeting and speaking with the people who made up the conference. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tiffapiffa&quot;&gt;Tiffany Duening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AndrewRocco&quot;&gt;Andy Rossi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sawyermaigen&quot;&gt;Maigan Sawyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ryanhartsock&quot;&gt;Ryan Hartsock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chrisdavidgfx&quot;&gt;Chris David G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alextheduck27&quot;&gt;Alex Grigas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HouseofGrays&quot;&gt;Megan Gray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/evies&quot;&gt;Evie Shaffer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/daveonkels&quot;&gt;Dave Onkels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just click through some of those profiles, Dribbble accounts, blogs, etc. You can&amp;#8217;t help but be inspired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same was true of XOXO &amp;#8211; which I sort of see as a gathering of artists and inventors (a gross over generalization, I know). The &amp;#8220;d-word&amp;#8221; (disruption) was used sparingly, but the &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; permeated almost every talk and discussion. To what end? Not surprisingly, almost every talk touched on the idea of community &amp;#8211; people coming together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the wonderful people I met at XOXO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wanderingmatt&quot;&gt;Matthew Anderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/atnan&quot;&gt;Nathan de Vries&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yarrcat&quot;&gt;Ros Hodgekiss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/chrismessina&quot;&gt;Chris Messina&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brynn&quot;&gt;Brynn Evans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tempo&quot;&gt;Thor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmyGSFN&quot;&gt;Amy Muller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sonaar&quot;&gt;Sonaar Luthra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikerugnetta&quot;&gt;Mike Rugnetta&lt;/a&gt; (why this guy doesn&amp;#8217;t have more followers is crazy to me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and many others&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for me, if I had any takeaways from the two conferences, they almost certainly all collide in the intersection between community, creativity, disruption, and people &amp;#8211; particularly the people who make the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are awesome. That&amp;#8217;s my big revelation from this past week. No duh, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/people_of_the_internet</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/people_of_the_internet</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On #hashtags</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I read a geek opine about social trends it reminds me of Maciej Ceglowski’s post from a few years ago entitled &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.pinboard.in/2011/11/the_social_graph_is_neither/&quot;&gt;The Social Graph is Neither&lt;/a&gt;. His main assertion was that we are a bunch of admittedly non-social engineers designing and building software – social networks – for a system that is so wildly complex that it cannot be graphed. What’s so entertaining to me, is not only do we attempt to design, build, and graph it, we also love to criticize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, when hashtags first started appearing in my Twitter timeline, I just sort of shrugged them off. I couldn’t see their value through the visual damage they imposed. Even today, I have a hard time #taking #anyone #seriously when they use more than one or two #hashtags for a #single #tweet – mostly because they just &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Victor recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2013/03/hashtags-considered-harmful/&quot;&gt;wrote about this&lt;/a&gt;, saying he believes “a tweet free of hashtags is more pleasing to the eye, more easily consumed, and thus more likely to be retweeted (which is a proven way of growing your audience)”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now here’s where I have to admit I have come to realize three important facts about hashtags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hashtags are used by both users and marketers&lt;/strong&gt;. Like it or not, you cannot deny usage of hashtags is on the rise. The most compelling thing about this is that hashtags weren&amp;#8217;t created as a marketing tactic, yet their use has demanded marketer adoption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hashtags do have great potential&lt;/strong&gt;. Even in their most basic form &amp;#8211; for taxonomy &amp;#8211; hashtags can trump inferral through machines. No one knows better what they&amp;#8217;re saying than the person saying it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hashtags actually do increase engagement&lt;/strong&gt;. It may be tough to recognize through subjectivity, but the reality is, hashtags provide a mechanism for easier discovery, encourage brevity, promote a single key binding for disparate data, and even help inject tone/personality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those three factors are so strong, in fact, that &lt;a href=&quot;http://tagboard.com&quot;&gt;I co-founded a company&lt;/a&gt; that is basically built on top of hashtags. At Tagboard, we’re building tools that help both users and marketers use hashtags in a way that benefits both parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opinion of hashtags is admittedly biased, and the root of my distaste for them is my design sense; they just look bad. Meanwhile, the engineer in me sees the yet-unrealized potential hashtags have. And then “Sensible Sean” sees hashtags as just harmless and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/on_hashtags</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/on_hashtags</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marketers are liars, not makers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When Seth Godin talks, I usually listen. I&amp;#8217;ve read his books and follow (albeit loosely) his blog. So when a bunch of my peers began linking to a post of his yesterday, along with negative commentary, I was immediately interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His post is titled &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/12/how-to-make-a-website-a-tactical-guide-for-marketers.html&quot;&gt;How to make a website: a tactical guide for marketers&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;, and if ever there was a list of bad starts of blogs posts, that one has to rank up there. I&amp;#8217;ll explain why in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post outlines various techniques Godin uses to make a website &amp;#8211; including copy/pasting elements from other sites in Keynote. Obviously, this isn&amp;#8217;t a website, so the last step in Godin&amp;#8217;s tactical guide is &amp;#8220;Hand the Keynote doc to your developers and go away…&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His expertise in marketing notwithstanding, this advice for how to &amp;#8216;make a website&amp;#8217; is terrible. I appreciate Godin&amp;#8217;s attempt at demystifying the process, and I recognize that giving practical advice for how marketers can work with their teams has great potential benefit. However, he would have done better to avoid the use of the words &amp;#8216;make&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;build&amp;#8217; altogether, and instead outlined how marketers can learn to make purposeful, high-level design decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Godin argues that most of the web is built by amateurs. And in what could be considered a followup post, goes on to say the &amp;#8220;best professionals love it when a passionate amateur shows up&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; and, of course, uses a couple of comparisons, like farmers and automotive mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with Godin&amp;#8217;s perspective (and comparisons) is he thinks marketers are builders. He says &amp;#8220;professional farmers don&amp;#8217;t begrudge the backyard gardener his tomato harvest. That&amp;#8217;s silly.&amp;#8221; And, he&amp;#8217;s right, because the backyard gardener is just that: a gardener. If, however, that gardener was a marketer who didn&amp;#8217;t know anything about the science of growing vegetables, but who was growing them (in spite of himself) and selling them on the open market, and competing for market- and mind-share with reputable farmers…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, let&amp;#8217;s just say I disagree that marketers &amp;#8216;make websites&amp;#8217;. They may be part of the process, but to suggest they can just throw together a slide deck and hand it off to a developer, and say they&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8216;building the web&amp;#8217; … &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; is silly. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/all_marketers_are_liars/&quot;&gt;Marketers are liars&lt;/a&gt;, not makers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/marketers_are_liars_not_makers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/marketers_are_liars_not_makers</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ichiro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After watching Ichiro play against the Mariners for the first time last night, I sat on my couch reading the reaction of Seattle sports fans on the web. I came across this piece on Tumblr: &lt;a href=&quot;http://theartofcompetition.tumblr.com/post/27893499063/there-was-no-joy-in-the-emerald-city&quot;&gt;There Was No Joy In The Emerald City&lt;/a&gt;. The author says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I feel shorted as a baseball fan today. The game was better when Ichiro was ominously roaming the right field region at Safeco Field. It was a welcome dose of predictability in an unpredictable game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this expresses well the overall sentiment in Seattle. We&amp;#8217;re all just sort of reeling. Happy for Ichiro? Sure. He has a much better shot at getting a championship ring now. But he was a part of Seattle culture &amp;#8211; as much as an athlete can up here. We had Ichiro bobble-head nights at Safeco Field, local commercials with every day workers mimicking his at-bat stance, and the &amp;#8220;ICH-EE-RO&amp;#8221; chant. Not to mention his face and name plastered all over the city &amp;#8211; especially at the stadium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tumblr_m7niloN21I1qbt9u6o1_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ichiro bowing as a Yankee&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was by Ichiro&amp;#8217;s request, I understand. That the Mariners received a couple of minor leaguer pitchers in trade underscores this: the Mariners made the decision in order to honor Ichiro. That part of the story is great, and I wish Ichiro well. I really do. I&amp;#8217;ll be rooting for him and his new team &amp;#8211; hopefully all the way through the World Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also business and internal culture reasons the Mariners made the trade. Ichiro&amp;#8217;s salary and veteran overhead are now cleared, making way for the youngsters to step up. That part I can understand, too. That&amp;#8217;s baseball. That&amp;#8217;s the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part that stings, and the part I&amp;#8217;m so frustrated by, is that Seattle continues to be burned by our sports organizations, who, in their attempt at trying to produce winning teams, keep messing with established culture; always looking to the future. They fail to understand the external, brand impact. They&amp;#8217;re trying to make Yankee-like decisions in a non-Yankee city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a news flash for Northwest sports teams: your fans aren&amp;#8217;t really fans. We&amp;#8217;re more like casual spectators, at best. If you want to win us over &amp;#8211; have our money &amp;#8211; you have to appeal to our emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why, when we&amp;#8217;re winning, Seattle gets &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; into it. Winning feels good. But after the winning season(s) ends, what&amp;#8217;s left to get emotional about? I&amp;#8217;ll tell you what: the brand &amp;#8211; which is best represented by the players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There might be a small segment of &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; fans, season ticket holders, and die-hards who were born here and have no choice but to take pride in their local professional teams. But those segments only make up an average attendance &amp;#8211; for the Mariners &amp;#8211; that equals the &lt;a href=&quot;http://espn.go.com/mlb/attendance&quot;&gt;fifth-worst in the league&lt;/a&gt;. Not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seattle sports culture extends beyond the small amount of actual fans. It goes to the living room, coffee house, and neighborhood community, where the majority of people now can&amp;#8217;t name a Mariners player on the roster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/ichiro</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/ichiro</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Obvious isn't easy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://om.co/2012/04/05/the-of-course-principle-of-design/&quot;&gt;lot&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2012/04/obviousness&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;http://dewith.com/2012/simplicity-and-obviousness/&quot;&gt;designing for obviousness&lt;/a&gt; in the design community lately. I just have one observation beyond agreement. Designing for obviousness is hard because you have to account for existing user conventions despite their weaknesses. That means good, obvious design has to take into account all three tenses: past, present, and future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/obvious_isnt_easy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/obvious_isnt_easy</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to unsubscribe from LinkedIn email</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In what I consider a necessary evil, I&amp;#8217;ve re-joined LinkedIn to, you know, &lt;em&gt;network&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s not really my choice, but I have to live with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of living with it is figuring out how to lessen the pain of dealing with all the  email they send. They&amp;#8217;re notorious for it. I&amp;#8217;ve done what I can in my profile settings, but unfortunately LinkedIn doesn&amp;#8217;t provide a toggle for receiving notifications of new connections. That means I&amp;#8217;m getting a new email for &lt;em&gt;every single new connection&lt;/em&gt; that is made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three ways to deal with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delete your LinkedIn account. I&amp;#8217;ve already taken this approach once, but it comes with the cost of not being able to, you know, &lt;em&gt;network&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set up some sort of client-side filter system. This doesn&amp;#8217;t work for me since the iPhone Mail app doesn&amp;#8217;t have filters. (Neither does &lt;a href=&quot;http://sparrowmailapp.com/iphone.php&quot;&gt;Sparrow&lt;/a&gt; at this point, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use another email address as your primary email. This is actually so smart, I&amp;#8217;m not sure why I hadn&amp;#8217;t already used it across all my various profiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea that you use a custom email alias (e.g. &amp;#8220;linkedin@domain.com&amp;#8221;) and a single email account/inbox that&amp;#8217;s not your primary address. Think of it like an email junk drawer. The requirements, obviously, are that you have control of your own domain, and that you can easily create email aliases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I have mine set up is similar to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://seansperte.com/entry/spam_free_email_for_the_iphone&quot;&gt;spam-free email setup&lt;/a&gt;. I have an email account called &amp;#8216;spam&amp;#8217;, and I&amp;#8217;m pointing &lt;code&gt;linkedin@*&lt;/code&gt; to that account. That way I can still access the account when/if I need (for confirmations, password resets, etc.), but don&amp;#8217;t get the obnoxious notifications or newsletters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only caveat is that friends and family won&amp;#8217;t be able to find my profile using my email address when they sign up or look for contacts. And, obviously, I&amp;#8217;m not really unsubscribed. But now I won&amp;#8217;t have my inbox flooded with LinkedIn Connection notifications either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/how_to_unsubscribe_from_linkedin_email</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/how_to_unsubscribe_from_linkedin_email</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Plain text in a field</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me start off this post by ensuring you that I have, in fact, tried the notes app you use and love and think is the best and want to recommend to me. I&amp;#8217;ve tried them all. A few I can recite, from memory: Byword, Elements, iA Writer, Quick Note, Note, Simplenote, Notational Velocity, nvAlt, Nottingham, Apple Mail, Write Room, VoodooPad, Notesy, Evernote, PlainText, OneNote, DEVONthink…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;#8217;m being too ambitious, thinking I can have a simple text editor combo (desktop and mobile app) that is just the right amount of simplicity without sacrificing function. Maybe I&amp;#8217;m naive to think that Apple&amp;#8217;s Notes app on iOS is &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; perfect, but would be better if it supported some form of simple organization scheme. Maybe I&amp;#8217;m stupid to suggest that a desktop app feel like it was made for the Mac, but not weighed down with feature-bloat and mostly useless functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what, in my mind, would make for the perfect desktop and mobile combination note taking apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Desktop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the desktop it doesn&amp;#8217;t take much. &lt;a href=&quot;http://notational.net/&quot;&gt;Notational Velocity&lt;/a&gt; is almost there, but drives me nuts with it&amp;#8217;s strange (to the Mac) experience conventions. One example is with the creation of a new note &amp;#8211; why in the world can&amp;#8217;t I create a new note with ⌘-N? Those kinds of oddities or omissions are deal-breakers for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perfect desktop notes app would:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a single window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contain a listing of notes in a sidebar (I don&amp;#8217;t want to have to use an open dialog or the Finder to open a note)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be completely useable with only the keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be light weight and quick, and feel native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/mountain-lion/features.html#notes&quot;&gt;Mountain Lion&amp;#8217;s Notes app&lt;/a&gt; looks promising, but is limited by lack of organizational functionality. Same goes for the iOS version(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;iOS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perfect mobile notes app should be similarly focussed. &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplenoteapp.com/&quot;&gt;Simplenote&lt;/a&gt; is near pitch-perfect here. It&amp;#8217;s just plain text in a field. It has a simple organizational schema (via tags), is quick and light weight, and has search. It&amp;#8217;s most glaring problem, for me, is its lack of desktop counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my ideal mobile notes app would:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be just like Simplenote, but have a desktop counterpart (and an icon that hints at its function, not its brand)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As an aside, can someone tell me why it&amp;#8217;s so hard for an iOS app to support moving of notes/files from one location on Dropbox to another?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The combination&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, it&amp;#8217;s the combination of &lt;em&gt;desktop plus mobile&lt;/em&gt; that I can&amp;#8217;t seem to find. I actually don&amp;#8217;t mind &lt;a href=&quot;http://evernote.com/&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; on the Mac (even though it&amp;#8217;s overkill for what I want), but don&amp;#8217;t like its iOS version(s). I like Simplenote on my iPhone, but there&amp;#8217;s no version for Mac (and the iPad version is sort of ho-hum). I&amp;#8217;m stuck in this no-man&amp;#8217;s land of apps that get passable grades on one platform but flunk the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, a notes app combo must:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be just plain text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not require a title for a note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a simple organizational scheme (folders or tags, either one works)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync (without fail)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it. That&amp;#8217;s all it takes to win me as a customer. If you want to charge me $19.99 for each app, that&amp;#8217;s fine. If you want to charge me $45 per year, that&amp;#8217;s fine, too. As long as you deliver on those items I listed above, you can have my money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/plain_text_in_a_field</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/plain_text_in_a_field</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A story about an iPad browser that never was</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we founded &lt;a href=&quot;http://skyballoonstudio.com&quot;&gt;Sky Balloon&lt;/a&gt; we endeavored to do one thing: make iOS (or, at the time, iPhone) software that we wanted. Because of that, after we successfully shipped our first iPhone app, &lt;a href=&quot;http://skyballoonstudio.com/rhema&quot;&gt;Rhema&lt;/a&gt;, we decided to tackle something a bit more ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was May or June of 2010 (I can&amp;#8217;t remember exactly) and we were loving our brand new iPads … except for the web browser, Safari. While advancements had been made in terms of its speed, we felt it still lacked in features and experience implementation &amp;#8211; or UI. So we had the brilliant idea to make a new browser for the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I should say, &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; had the idea, because &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; had no idea what it took to build software, and &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; figured we could do it. You know, with our three-man team that only met for a few hours per week. And because, after all, we were only going to be building a great &amp;#8220;frame&amp;#8221; around a UIWebView. And Apple already did the hard part by building the renderer. And, how hard could it be? Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that building a browser is curse-word hard, even if you don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about the rendering of web pages. At the time, though, we didn&amp;#8217;t know this. Well, maybe the other two thirds of our little company did. But they were brave enough to follow me and my naivety into battle anyway, despite their better judgment, and armed only with Xcode and &lt;a href=&quot;http://seansperte.com/share/breeze-mockups/&quot;&gt;some mockups&lt;/a&gt; I had whipped up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was that we&amp;#8217;d create a browser that we would want to use, market to all our internet buddies, hopefully get featured on &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macworld.com/channels/ios.html&quot;&gt;Macworld&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://twit.tv/mbw&quot;&gt;MacBreak Weekly&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuaw.com/&quot;&gt;TUAW&lt;/a&gt; or some other hugely populated website full of enthusiasts, be spotlighted by Apple as an example of innovation on the iPad (despite competing toe-to-toe with Safari), and make millions. Then we&amp;#8217;d keep making apps and stuff. From our yachts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come to think of it, I&amp;#8217;m not sure we actually had a plan. We just knew we wanted a better browser &amp;#8211; one with the features I&amp;#8217;m about to outline &amp;#8211; and I had imagined one up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/breeze-icon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Breeze icon&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;130&quot; height=&quot;147&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;We called it Breeze. Like, &amp;#8220;this browser is such a breeze to use&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;wow, browsing with this app is so easy&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;honey, come look at these chumps who made a web browser like Safari and are trying to be cool naming it a one-word, nondescript noun&amp;#8221;. The tagline was, &amp;#8220;Browse more awesomely on iPad.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m so embarrassed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, but the features. Check out these features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we&amp;#8217;d rid the toolbar of the two distinct input fields &amp;#8211; only one &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chromium.org/user-experience/omnibox&quot;&gt;omnibox&lt;/a&gt;-inspired location bar, capable of both search and URL input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next &amp;#8211; and this seemed so obvious to us we were sure Apple would steal it for Safari &amp;#8211; a history popover when you tap-and-hold the back button. This, as expected, was added to Safari later. We&amp;#8217;re still uncertain how Apple hacked into our Dropbox accounts, but they somehow got their hands on the idea. (I think the guys suspect I was responsible, since I have some friends at Apple. But whatever.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, our UI was going to be cleaner and more refined, since, you know, I&amp;#8217;m so much better a graphic designer than those hacks at Apple, Inc. So the polished UI was also to be a feature listed on the App Store description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we come to the good stuff. Our tabs really were something to behol&amp;#8211;oh, crap. I forgot, Apple added our tabs to Safari recently. Anyway, this is what they looked like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/breeze-tabs_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Breeze tabs&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;84&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those were coded up, by the way. That&amp;#8217;s not a Photoshop mockup. And you have to remember, back then Safari&amp;#8217;s tabs weren&amp;#8217;t tabs at all. They were a 3x3 grid view of web pages that often needed to be reloaded once switched to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only had three tabs shown in the view, but the tab bar was horizontally scrollable to allow for unlimited tabs. We also didn&amp;#8217;t show the tab bar until there were two tabs. &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/linked/2012/03/05/safari-52-tabs&quot;&gt;Gruber would (have) be(en) proud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our spotlight feature we were going to include, get this, a &amp;#8220;reading mode&amp;#8221;. Months prior I had discovered a bookmarklet for Safari on the Mac called Readability, that, when activated, would isolate just the text (and any relevant images) on a web page. We thought this was wonderful, and &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; to be on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Apple thought it &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; to be on the Mac too, because only a few weeks after we began development, Safari for Mac shipped with &amp;#8220;Reader Mode&amp;#8221;, powered by the Readability script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/breeze-readingmode.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Breeze readingmode&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;269&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;Although we knew Safari for iPad would likely get Reader Mode, we thought we could either (1) get there first, or (2) do ours better. We designed a couple of really great themes for Breeze&amp;#8217;s Reading Mode, and decided that, even if Apple beat us to the punch, our themes might be enough to hedge out a healthy and loyal user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I even got in touch with the company behind Readability (now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readability.com/&quot;&gt;a stand alone product and service&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arc90.com/&quot;&gt;Arc90&lt;/a&gt;, and asked if they&amp;#8217;d be willing to take a look at Breeze once we were ready to show. &lt;a href=&quot;http://arc90.com/people/rich-ziade/&quot;&gt;Rich Ziade&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; reply was enthusiastic, and he agreed. (In hindsight, I&amp;#8217;m pretty sure he was humoring me. Roles reversed, I would have.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there were all the features we knew we couldn&amp;#8217;t include in Breeze 1.0, but knew we wanted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad blocking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing modules (for social sites)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in child-protection and accountability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyword URL support (m = gmail.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find on page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gestures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were more, but I&amp;#8217;m too embarrassed to share. (Okay, one was &amp;#8220;Bing support&amp;#8221;. There, happy?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad part is that we really did get a lot of it built. In fact, by the time Apple finally shipped Safari with proper tabs we were readying a private beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Safari&amp;#8217;s slow-but-steady evolution, coupled with the third-party browser market (which had continued to expand to include great apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/app/icab-mobile-web-browser/id308111628?mt=8&quot;&gt;iCab&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grazingbrowser.com/&quot;&gt;Grazing&lt;/a&gt;), made Breeze&amp;#8217;s success harder and harder to imagine. We also realized that not shipping after about 14 months of development meant we&amp;#8217;d bitten off more than we could chew. And by then the delusions of grandeur that said we could be featured by Apple, or even John Gruber &amp;amp; Co., had worn off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made the hard decision to abandon the project, at what we estimate was 75% in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned a lot, though. Not just about iOS development, but also ourselves, the business of software, and about what we might be capable of if we didn&amp;#8217;t have just a few hours per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also: I can&amp;#8217;t wait &amp;#8216;til you see what we&amp;#8217;re working on now.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/entry/a_story_about_an_ipad_browser_that_never_was</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/entry/a_story_about_an_ipad_browser_that_never_was</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
